<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Considered Design</title>
    <description>I like solving interesting problems, for things that matter. Product designer. London, Rio, now Sydney.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 06:36:04 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 06:36:04 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The rhythm of our weeks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve found myself in a familiar place recently. Opening Slack at sunrise, responding to emails at dinner, doing busy work before bed. The bookends of the 9-5 have drifted, blurring the boundaries of life and work. Days slip by like this. My weeks are busy but unvaried, a wall of white noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of us work is always at hand, with always more to do. Ticking off a todo here and an email there helps us feel like we’re being useful, we have a purpose. Weeks like these are fine if they are rare. A big push to get a project over the line, starting something new on the side. It’s easy for this white noise work week to become the white noise work month, and before long you’re on a slow road to burn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overworking like this puts all my identity and self esteem into one vessel, and it becomes how I define myself. It has an outsized impact on my mood, which makes me feel too reactive, and to be frank, uninteresting. When this happens I need to look at my week with a different lens. To spot how I can make space for things I want to nurture, and amplify the things I enjoy in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-my-ratios&quot;&gt;Reflecting on my ratios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I could work less (which would have made for an even shorter post), but this is only part of the problem. Working is a default state when I’ve got nothing to displace it, but the white noise work weeks is also a reminder of all the things I’m not doing. I want my weeks to have rhythm and variety, that help create months with balance and fulfilment. Easy and enjoyable things to aim for, but to help be more specific I sketched out a goal of sorts. Things I want to be doing less of, things I want to do more of, and things I need to make space for. All to set a new, more fulfilling balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/ratio.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some need to happen in a particular location, some can happen anywhere. Some need a lot more energy and focus, others are a way to relax. The art of fulfilling weeks is finding the right balance between these things, and defending their time against the white noise work week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taking-stock-of-how-much-time-i-have&quot;&gt;Taking stock of how much time I have&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve been a little obsessive over how other people spend their days. Little tidbits of how they find balance and time for the things they are trying to maximise in their lives. I’ve tried Jessica Hische’s Ultra-Schedule, borrowed bits from My Morning Routine, and the simple wisdom of Mr Bingo. For a brief period whilst dating someone in a tax bracket I’ll never be in, even anecdotes from Lunch with the FT. Between artists and financiers, there is a common thread that connects them all. They are very intentional with what they spend their time on, and at which part of their day they do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/old-day.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at my days, after a good night’s sleep and other hard commitments, I have about 4 hours free a day. This all falls into one space after dinner, divvied up between work and Netflix. This isn’t my prime time brain time, but is a great home for “make space for” things like reading and creative practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/new-night.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, willing these to happen has not helped. For these to actually take root I’ve had to put them where the bad habits start. Leaving a book in progress on top of the TV remote, or making sure the iPad and Pencil charged and ready to use. The more intentional I can be with this, the harder it is for the white noise work week to creep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-my-days-better&quot;&gt;Starting my days better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m most creative, productive and receptive first thing in the morning. The earlier the better. Knowing this, and testing it’s limits, I moved my day back to the unholy hour of 5am. My new “selfish space”. I can work on whatever I want, and not feel like I’m displacing family time or sacrificing other spaces to work on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/new-morning.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again this isn’t perfect. Am I thinking and writing with perfect clarity at 5:06? Deeeeeefinitely not. For writing and side projects, these two hours are more than the energy and focus I have in the four after dinner. Like the “hour of sleep before midnight is worth two after”, but in reverse. Selfishly, spending time on myself first makes it much easier to focus and be present in the other spaces in my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-how-the-week-feels&quot;&gt;Reflecting on how the week feels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important space in my week is time to reflect. A handful of simple prompts, it let’s me think about how the rhythm of the week has been. What went well, what didn’t, and what should I change. As with most things in life, it’s far more about the feeling of how things contribute than the exact amounts. This used to be on Sunday night, but I’ve found this more easier first thing Friday morning. That way my weekends are obligation free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;multiply&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/reflection.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fulfilling-years-start-with-fulfilling-days&quot;&gt;Fulfilling years start with fulfilling days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a CEO once who had a mantra for hitting goals that went “daily, makes weekly, makes monthly, makes yearly”. A former statistician, he thought of this as a numbers game, but the compounding nature of it stuck with me. The time we spend in our days is how we’ll spend our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/year-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve been trying to “maximise” in my life has changed a lot over the years, especially since becoming a parent. The joy is being comfortable with that change, and re-scaffolding my week to support it. For now though, my white noise work week has faded. My weeks have their rhythm back, and I have a process to keep that on course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rhythm-of-our-weeks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rhythm-of-our-weeks/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The necessary exercise in writing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was talking to a close friend recently, someone who I think is a very good writer, who helps edit my excessive use of commas in sentences (he didn’t have time for this post), when he said he’s started to think of writing like exercise. A process that feels arduous and unpleasant, but once it’s all done, you just feel better for having done it. Another run under your belt. Another post out in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was funny because to me his writing seems effortless. Clever and witty opinions on a wide range of interesting topics. He’s got a nice balance of long and short posts, and for him, doing this on an increasingly regularly cadence is what’s keeping his writing skills in shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own writing, personal or published, happens very rarely. My personal best is I think is maybe 5 posts in a single year. My signature style is to find a topic I initially find interesting, hash out a first draft, then let it wither and decay in my drafts over the course of several months. Like a neglectful plant owner, apologetically watering a dry twig in a pot once a month, at the same time wondering why it’s not in full bloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully for my health, I do manage to do slightly more exercise in a year. Current habit is a few runs a week, but a habit I’m happy to break, because as you’ll know if you’ve ever tried it — running is awful. Aside from listening to Off Menu during it, to convince myself through association running is fun, the only thing that has helped it be slightly less awful is varying the types of runs I do in the week. A mix of short runs, long runs and intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mondays are my short run days. Running loops around the local oval, it’s a bumbling 5k to ease me into the week. Purely and horribly pragmatic, this morning run is really just for two things. To signal to my weekend brain that it’s time is up, and to condition myself for the longer, more challenging run on Friday. The small joy of this shorter Monday run is I don’t need to think about it. No excessive stretching, no prep, just put my gear on and head out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My writing never gets these short runs, and it shows. When I’m stumbling through a frustrated attempt at a longer post, it’s not reading about how to be a better writer that’ll help, or give me the stamina to finish it. It’s the habit of getting a few miles on the clock here and there. Small opportunities to get a post out, however long, to break the cycle and release the pressure of finishing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy writing, so much more than I’ll ever enjoy running, so I’m wary of putting too much structure around it as a habit. Thinking of it like exercise though is the perfect way to quiet the thinking that every post has to attempt to break some personal PB, or be the best exercise I can get. Sometimes a brisk morning 5k is just enough to feel content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/necessary-exercise-in-writing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/necessary-exercise-in-writing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shot on iPhone, forgotten forever</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To put it mildly, it’s been a weird time for everyone recently. I was due to fly home to London for a visit in April, but because my Mum is in a high risk category, I’d be in quarantine for as long as the trip was originally booked for, and we needed to cancel the trip. Even if we lived next door we wouldn’t be able to visit now, but not being allowed to see her in London, or my wife’s parents in New Zealand, it makes us all feel a little further than we are. Our saving grace in all this? Mia’s Moments, our family WhatsApp group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken more pictures in my daughter’s first year than I have in the 5 parent free years before that. Every first and every fall is faithfully captured, and sent with a caption to Mia’s Moments. Her first day. Her first bath. Her first giggle. A steadily growing timeline of her life, which during this time of isolation, has been our fallback for family connection. With this group no one is missing out, and no group is closer than the other. In the best possible way, we’re all just at an arm’s length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/born.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/mia-passport.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/ball.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the chat we’ve talked about how lucky we are to capture and share moments like this so easily, and how different it was when we were kids. With film cameras, each picture had a mix of uncertainty and anticipation waiting for it to be developed. They had to be more selective about what moments were worth capturing, and having to pay to get them developed also created a sense of occasion. We used burst mode to capture Mia eating her first birthday cake. A disposable Kodak only had 27 chances to capture the entire day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve always loved about film though; it has the useful physical prompt to make you more likely to do something with it. To frame it somewhere, stick it on the fridge, or slip into a laminated photo album with a shorthand for the memory — “Dom, 4 months old, with Uncle Joe. Marsh Green”. Displayed in the hallway of your home, put on the mantelpiece, or on the dresser by your bed — you’re able to bring a memory into a place you want it to be remembered and relived, so it’s not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mia’s Moments is the closest ritual we have for flicking through a photo album, but it’s more to dip in and out of than a way to cement them as memories, or to externalise them from our phones and into the home. What we all love about it, though, is that we can just scroll through it to feel close to each other. A shared family highlight reel. I find myself going through these images of Mia regularly, exhausted on the couch in front of something shit on Netflix, and often think about how nice a private curated stream would be for other groups of people and moments in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My photos are not in a place to make this easy — I’ve got nearly 20 thousand images on my phone, which makes it impossible to seperate something that is genuinely nostalgic from the sea of noise. My iCloud Library, with all it’s metadata and history of my travel, has no easy way to quickly curate and share something with people I’m thinking of. Lockdown or not, the thought of retroactively organising something I’ve been so mindless about feels too big to be worthwhile. Thousands of images spread over years in different cities, different jobs, and different social circles. Not exactly a tupperware drawer I konmari my way out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think part of why we take so many pictures is there’s a tiny comfort in capturing a moment, even if it is an illusion of preserving it in memory. Colourful manhole covers in Japan, taken on a walk with friends in Hakuba. An ornate ferry token in New Zealand, during a trip for someone’s 30th. A picture of a pint from a trip home with a close mate in London — these are all moments I’d love to remember and relive, but have quickly faded from memory as soon as I’ve taken them and locked my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/hakuba.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/coffee.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/ferry.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Faded memories from Japan, Sydney and New Zealand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some I could print and frame somewhere, there is a finite amount of space in my home to put them. What I’d find more valuable is being able to surface pictures of certain people and moments in my photos when I want to, or when would be meaningful to be reminded of them. The problem with this is my iPhone is completely unaware of the emotional context of my pictures and the people in them. Is that an ex, or an old school friend? A reunion, or a Monday? My first picture with someone, or my last?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a small but meaningful change adding a “People” tab to the Photos app, and connecting it to other Apple services. My closest friends live in London and New York, and we’ve got an iMessage group that must be nearly 10 years old, and is still active almost daily. The People tab could easily group photos of us through that group (the same way it does on the newer share options). It could show me the photos and memories we have together, and be a way to surface those natively in iMessage, or a path to FaceTime them directly from a memory in Photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/pixar.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;At an exhibition with close friends visiting a Cooper Hewitt exhibition in New York&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;At an exhibition with close friends visiting a Cooper Hewitt exhibition in New York&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this kind of memory assistant to keep me connected to people I care about would also help me with the emotional labour staying connected can sometimes feel like, especially in times like this. Whilst I wait for technology to magically solve this for me, there are some blunter ways I might be able to fold this into individual practice. I could set a weekly reminder to go through images I’ve taken each week, to tag people and the missing context just outside of the frame. Create a location based shortcut to intentionally select highlights on my commute (whenever that’s a thing again). Share more moments in posts like these. Maybe private blog posts just for closest friends. This all might prove to be more work than it’s worth. For now at least, I have Mia’s Moments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/shot-on-iphone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/shot-on-iphone/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shortcuts for automated bliss</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well everyone, I’ve finally done it. I’ve cemented Shortcuts in my life, and I’m happy to say I’m well on my way to automated bliss. I’ve attempted to find this bliss a few times — with IFTTT, with the previously named Workflow, with the rarely working smart bulbs — but after getting the Apple Watch last year, setting complex things like laundry timers was easier, and the need for Syndrome like power ebbed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As 2020 rolled in though, I saw someone using a Shortcut to revert one of the most annoying behaviours in iOS (low battery mode being turned off after it hits 85%), and I started playing around with it again. Maybe in part because I can’t really code, but it’s both empowering and exciting to create Shortcuts, and there is a tinkering aspect to it which is deeply enjoyable. A feeling mirrored by Khoi Vin in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtraction.com/2019/12/04/shortcuts-and-screenshots-on-ios/&quot;&gt;his recent post on Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; — it’s also easily possible to spend far more time on them that they could possibly ever save you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a handful I’m using daily now, and think they’re at a place that others might find them useful now too. The music one below was even enough to make me switch from Spotify to Apple Music (currently not possible to automate or shortcut anything with Spotify), and having artwork again to browse through without being pushed to their own discovery sections, I’ve really enjoyed. Once I figure how to host these I’ll include the iCloud links so others can use them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focus-work--approachable-work&quot;&gt;Focus work &amp;amp; approachable work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the right conditions to do focus work is really important to me, and it’s always boiled down to two things; removing as many distractions as I can, and and giving others the signals that I’m doing focus work so I won’t be disturbed. The more clear and repeatable the prompts and routine are for me, the more pavlovian my response is, and the easier I find it to get into that focus state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds silly (maybe even sad knowing I come from London), but the best focus prompt I have is rain in noise cancelling headphones. Combining that with no notifications flying into my view, and I’m as distraction free as it’s possible to get (handled by 1-3 in this shortcut).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing big noise cancelling headphones is a good physical signal you’re doing focus work (although as we know, not aaaalways respected), but at Qwilr we also have distributed teams, so I wanted to be able to signal it clearly on Slack to everyone is most useful to me. I’ve tried this a few different ways before (using a combination of IFTTT &amp;amp; Glitch), but it was really unreliable, and after a few maiden voyages just stopped working altogether. This new setup works perfectly, but to do the Slack shortcuts it runs you’ll need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/custom-integrations/legacy-tokens&quot;&gt;create your personal Slack token&lt;/a&gt; to replace mine, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/methods/users.profile.set/test&quot;&gt;use their methods here&lt;/a&gt; to spit out the url with your token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a playback device (useful if I’m wearing headphones or not)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plays my Focus playlist (rain track)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turns on do not disturb on all my devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates my Slack status, sets me away, and puts on DND&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s me select a timer for how long I want to do focus work for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-g.PNG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The steps to run the Focus work Shortcut, including the Slack api call for setting presence&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set my slack status was a little more complicated (for some reason I couldn’t get it to work through the same url schemes as above), but found &lt;a href=&quot;https://routinehub.co/shortcut/2443&quot;&gt;this Shortcut from Jake Bathman really useful&lt;/a&gt; (he also has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jakebathman/setting-up-a-slack-app-for-use-with-ios-shortcuts-e8e16b15d0f3&quot;&gt;accompanying post here too&lt;/a&gt;). His Shortcut let’s you put in a custom text status each time, but as I just wanted to set a specific one each time, I cut a few of the steps out, and now mine looks like this, with a step above this which uses text to set my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SlackOAuthToken&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-d.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-e.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-f.PNG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Using variables and dictionary to set a specific slack status&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-to-my-discovery-playlist&quot;&gt;Adding to my Discovery playlist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My memory iiiiiis not great, and to help with that I’ve always had a habit of writing down songs I like as I hear them. A personal torture for me is waking up after being somewhere, remembering very clearly I heard a new/great/nostalgic song I liked, but having only maybe a melody of it I will never, ever be able to google and find. The problem before is I’d have this huge list of songs in Things, which I then had to look up in Spotify to play them. With this Shortcut, I’m able to bypass that list and add songs I hear directly to a Discovery playlist. I then have another Shortcut to play this playlist, ordering songs by oldest to newest, so I’m not just replaying the same songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps-1&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s me enter a search query&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shows me a list of matching song results&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can select as many matches as I want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selected songs are added to my Discovery playlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/discovery.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;An example using an art marker (1) and the level of detail in the capture putting a head(2) and a statue (3) onto a desk&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;An example using an art marker (1) and the level of detail in the capture putting a head(2) and a statue (3) onto a desk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facetime-roulette&quot;&gt;Facetime Roulette&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important background context on this one — I find staying in touch with people I don’t see regularly really challenging. I’ve never been great at it, but living in a timezone 11 hours ahead has made it much harder. Part of it is I detest anything that makes something that’s not work feel like work. So the idea of putting a call with a close friend in the calendar so we don’t forget to do it I avoid like the plague. Facetime Roulette is actually an idea for an app I had ages ago, and although it doesn’t have everything (ideally I’d want to bias the roulette to people I hadn’t called in ages etc), this shortcut gets me most of the way there. I’m going to use this for a few months, and if it hold the magical appeal I think having a roulette layer to staying in touch with friends will have, I’ll develop the concept out more into an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps-2&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grabs a specific contact group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orders it by random&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limits the selection to one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FaceTimes that lucky roulette winner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/facetime-roulette.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-play&quot;&gt;Further play&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few other Shortcuts I’m playing with at the moment, but haven’t got quite right yet. All solving the big problems in life — fade out the nursery light and fade in white noise, triggering the office logo to do a rainbow loop on a launch — but I’ll keep tinkering and share them when they’re done. If you’re interested in creating your own, the best places I found were the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/shortcuts/&quot;&gt;Shortcuts subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://shortcutsgallery.com&quot;&gt;Shortcuts Gallery&lt;/a&gt;. Both buzzing with hobbyist creators, and also very eager to answer questions — enjoy 🙂.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/shortcuts-for-automated-bliss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/shortcuts-for-automated-bliss/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The quest for undeniable bestness</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;full-width-hero&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/quest-large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help frame this post, I want to begin by sharing a snippet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.qwilr.com/gTndRdDyT7mY&quot;&gt;Qwilr’s driving Principles&lt;/a&gt;, written by our Founder &amp;amp; CEO, Dylan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We succeed not by taking hack shortcuts, not by social engineering or political machination, or short-term hot-air strategies, but by working resolutely and systemically to become the best. And not just the best, but the Undeniable Best, a superiority which once experienced, cannot be argued with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early June this year, my first project as Head of Design was to improve the way you create and manage custom project styles in Qwilr; to discover and design what Undeniable Bestness for this set of features might be. In the past 6 months we’ve completely redesigned how we think about and manage styles, and built an entirely new approach for our users. We’ve tested it internally, have beta users running through it as I type this, with some even using it on their live projects. The problem is it’s still not right — it simply does not meet our standard of Undeniable Bestness. So while I’d love to announce today our amazing and clever new solution, there’s a little more to it, and I wanted to be as transparent as possible as to why we are not launching this feature this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-starting-point&quot;&gt;The starting point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the redesign, every project you had on Qwilr came with a handful of preset styles to choose from. These presets managed the alignment and colour of that section, the available colours being whatever was set as the global brand colours on your account. What worked really well with this approach was being able to quickly browse styles to see which one was best suited to your content, with minimal decision tax. The main problem, though, was that anything you wanted to edit (either font size, individual item colour or alignment), all had to be done with CSS. It looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/styles-before-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;Menu for browsing style presets&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Menu for browsing style presets&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a large group of our users, having just a few preset styles without needing to edit anything worked great — you choose Qwilr specifically because it helps to enable better design outcomes with minimal decision making. But for another growing group of Qwilr users, not being able to directly edit and customise styles is limiting. You want it to feel like a natural extension of their brand, and to do this you need better style controls. In this case, Qwilr is likely being used across a larger team, which also introduces the idea of design or brand owners, who want to create styles their team uses without being able to edit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long story short, our users had simply outgrown how we’d thought about custom styles. We needed to rethink how we could create something better: something that empowered the growing variety of teams using Qwilr for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;revisiting-the-core-experience&quot;&gt;Revisiting the core experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting this redesign was a good opportunity to understand the mindset users have when starting to use Qwilr. The tools people are most familiar with before switching to Qwilr range from Microsoft Word to Adobe Indesign — and they both act as important framers for how people expect Qwilr to work. Both give very different expectations of how styles are created and managed, and our approach had to meet and leverage that familiarity to how Qwilr does things. For this, we needed a guiding question to help navigate uncertainty throughout the design process, and get us as close as possible to what users really needed. After a few brainstorming and unpacking sessions, we arrived at this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How can we make creating and managing custom styles a fast and empowering experience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rethinking-the-style-editor&quot;&gt;Rethinking the style editor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our guiding question in place, we started at the hardest area first — the editor used to create new styles. After speaking with a bunch of users, our initial design work focussed on having controls for every element in the block, to expand what could be controlled. This included controls for styling the heading, and separate controls the subheading etc. It made what should feel like a quick thing to change actually feel overwhelming with the choices available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/style-editor-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;Early UI designs for the style editor&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Early UI designs for the style editor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;early-ui-designs-for-the-style-editor&quot;&gt;Early UI designs for the style editor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways this was great, because it surfaced all the controls a user needed to edit style, really minimising the dependency on CSS. In other ways though, it was quite far removed from Qwilr’s design principles. For lack of better wording, it just didn’t feel right to use, and was overcomplicating the process. To help highlight this a bit better, here’s a little insight into our design process, for how we order our ideas when we create new features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/design-principles.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bearing this in mind, we thought about how we can reduce the number of UI controls, without loosing any style control. We started experimenting with how we could group multiple controls into one, so creating styles could be faster, and easier to get good design outcomes. This is quite close to how we as designers think about creating designs for documents and websites, and was a way to keep all the text as part of the same size relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/style.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Style controls manipulating text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Style controls manipulating text&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After testing this round with users, it seemed like a good compromise between good outcomes without going overboard on controls. The feedback at this stage though made it clear we’d still need to expand on our style controls going forward, and being in the same view didn’t give it much room to grow over time. To tackle this, we moved everything into a style editor overlay, which gave the editing experience a little more focus, and gave us important space to grow the feature down the track as and when we needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/style-editor-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Style editor overlay&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Style editor overlay&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;upgrading-the-style-browser&quot;&gt;Upgrading the style browser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great (although not unexpected) side effect of being able to quickly create more expressive styles, was a need to improve how we preview those styles, so you can quickly find the one you’re looking for. The previous design had a small thumbnail about half the size of a stamp, which used little blocks to represent the colours and alignment of the heading, subheading and body text. The problem with our design ideas, was we were introducing new sizes for all the text, which made using this mini preview harder to distinguish between similar styles. Here’s an example to highlight the difficulty:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/style-tiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;Although similar outcome, differentiating between styles at a glance is difficult&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Although similar outcome, differentiating between styles at a glance is difficult&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@dominosebastian/introducing-our-all-new-image-carousel-e428d5547849&quot;&gt;releasing the new Image Carousel&lt;/a&gt;, we thought the carousel would also fit well to browse your styles. Initially we were using mini previews of the block, using demo text shrunken down so you could see how the style might be applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/carousel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Earlier design iteration of the carousel with text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Earlier design iteration of the carousel with text&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this was quite an effective preview, it actually looked really messy and overwhelming when it was open. It felt like a slow, burdened choice, and wasn’t particularly fun to use — it was ignoring our guiding principle of being empowering and fast to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we settled on re-using the block visualisation, just at a bigger scale to see the differences, with their style names. While it feels visually simpler, and in theory should work well for our varied (and growing) block types, we still think we can do better. Creating a visual shorthand for blocks is challenging, especially when you don’t want to overwhelm with details and choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/carousel-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;Latest working iteration of the carousel with blocks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Latest working iteration of the carousel with blocks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style editor is in a much better place than when we started this project, but along the way while grouping some of the actions, it’s lost a little of the directness users need. The part that’s really missing for it to be it’s Undeniable Best, is this should feel like a superior and faster editing experience, regardless of what users are familiar with. At the moment, it’s not there yet, and releasing this now would be a disservice to those that need it in their workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the style carousel feels visually simpler, it’s also still not quite where we want it to be, and has the added complication of needing these previews for all our new (and growing) block types. Once you’ve created your styles, this is the part you interact with the most frequently, so we’re still working on this being a really smooth, enjoyable experience. Something we’ll be putting into the back of our brains over the next few months to chew over, and come back to the problem with fresh eyes and minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring us back to the point that started all this reflection, I want to share another snippet from our Principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Undeniable Bestness means being hard on ourselves and have strong personal benchmarks of quality. It means accommodating to a permanent state of dissatisfaction. This dissatisfaction is a good thing. It keeps us productive. It keeps us pushing ourselves forward. Whenever we reach a summit, we’re already looking to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a great book recently which had an apt analogy about what makes a great artist. They need to be able to hone in and focus on the details of each brush stroke, whilst being able to step back and see how each stroke fits into the larger composition. Internally at Qwilr, the process of designing this feature to meet our principles has helped our ability to take that step back to see the larger view. It’s highlighted areas of our process we’re actively improving, such as prototyping our ideas more thoroughly early in the process, and unpacking the problem with a more user-centred mindset. It’s also helped us design a more meaningful approach to large features like this, so we can turn around and deliver the best solutions to you all, in a way we’re proud to say has achieved it’s true, Undeniable Best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-very-special-thanks-to-our-users&quot;&gt;A very special thanks to our users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I won’t ever get tired of saying is how great our users are. Personally, I want to say a huge, huge thank you to everyone that has helped and continues to help us beta test not just custom styles but all our features. Taking the time and risk of using something new on your live projects, whilst being open and transparent about what’s not working and what could be improved is exactly what guides us in delivering the best solutions we can. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/quest-for-undeniable-bestness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/quest-for-undeniable-bestness/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing our all-new Image Carousel</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;full-width-hero&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/image-carousel-large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At it’s core, &lt;a href=&quot;www.qwilr.com&quot;&gt;Qwilr&lt;/a&gt; is a communication design tool. Whilst we began as a way for people to create proposals as beautiful web pages, it’s grown to be used for case studies, landing pages, online brochures and much more. All things that rely on great imagery to be persuasive. The trouble was our image browsing experience hadn’t grown with these new use cases, and needed a lot of love and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, after wrapping up testing with our fan-tastic beta group, I’m very excited to announce an all new image browsing experience, called the Image Carousel. From today in Qwilr, you’ll now have access to thousands of high-quality and free to use images, without leaving your project, to make your proposals even more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YRaBDsNjonU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-we-used-to-handle-images&quot;&gt;How we used to handle images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before, when you needed to add in an image to your project, you’d be presented with an overlay, where you could select one of the images we had in our collection, or upload your own. It looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/image-browser-old.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a handful of issues with this design. A few were well understood functional gaps, like not being able to search the library, or view images you’d recently used or uploaded. This can really affect repeated use, because each time you wanted to use an image in your project, it felt like you were starting from scratch again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These well understood issues aside, there was also a much larger and harder to define issue remaining; exploring the library and playing around with different image options felt like a long, burdened decision process. In any creative work, the longer the design decision takes, the more doubt will start to creep in over the outcome—and that’s the last thing we wanted. We want Qwilr to help facilitate fast, empowered design decisions that users love and are excited to share. As soon as we realised this, choosing great images with speed became the core focus in our design process. Below are a few key parts I’m very proud to share of the new design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/image-carousel-b.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;collections-in-context&quot;&gt;Collections in context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exploring a few different directions, we found the fastest way to find great imagery was to never leave the project itself. Instead, we could bring up the image library in context, exactly where you were working. With this we could present images grouped by a theme or collection, so trying alternatives is easier. We could cut finding an image down to two clicks, rather than the previous 5. Most importantly though — you could play with variations faster without losing momentum in your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/image-collections-context.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shuffle-to-find-something-new&quot;&gt;“Shuffle” to find something new&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you don’t know what image will work until you see it, and getting momentum in that early discovery phase is important to get past creative block. With the “Shuffle” button, clicking it puts a new collection at random into the carousel, so you can cycle through different themes faster when you’re stuck on what would work best with your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/image-browser.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullscreen-overlay-for-exploring-themes&quot;&gt;Fullscreen overlay for exploring themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we completely redesigned the fullscreen overlay experience, so it could house your recently used and uploaded images, and allow you to browse images and collections with a little more screen real estate. From here you can also add in any collection you find interesting to the carousel, to see how the images feel in the context of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-huge-huge-thanks-to-unsplash&quot;&gt;A huge, huge thanks to Unsplash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of this announcement is all these images are free, all thanks to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stephliverani/qwilr-unsplash-757bf110ce71&quot;&gt;partnership with Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;. In order to know how much this partnership means to us, I think it’s important to understand our mission as a company. The following is taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.qwilr.com/why-qwilr/&quot;&gt;Why Qwilr&lt;/a&gt;, written by our Founder &amp;amp; CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dylanbaskind.com/&quot;&gt;Dylan Baskind&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Qwilr’s mission is to liberate the web from this complexity. To make it a “speakable” language by anybody, anywhere. Rather than going to the web only for very special occasions, to build big complex websites that we expect to last for years, what if we could dash off a beautiful website in just a few minutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the above to happen, the question we constantly ask ourselves in design is how can users enjoy this speed without sacrificing quality? So far how we’ve achieved this at Qwilr is by starting with the best design defaults, and using simple but guided design controls to quickly achieve the desired outcome. Partnering with Unsplash is really a further commitment to giving our users the best design defaults we can, so they can create something better and faster than they thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this feature is now live for everyone, this doesn’t mean we are done with it. Through beta testing and early rounds of feedback, there’s a few things we are going to be improving over the coming months. And if you have any ideas or feedback around how we could make this better for you, you can email us here—we’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qwilr lets you create business documents as beautiful, mobile friendly websites, that are quick to create and impressive to receive. To find out more check out our website, and if you want to &lt;a href=&quot;https://qwilr.com/&quot;&gt;try Qwilr yourself&lt;/a&gt;, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://qwilr.com/signup&quot;&gt;signup here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/introducing-image-carousel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/introducing-image-carousel/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 – A brief year in review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a great year. In 2016 I was lucky enough to go to New Zealand, Hawaii, New York, London, Norway and Tokyo – whilst having a full time job. I submitted my permanent residency visa application in Australia, got promoted, and got engaged. Amongst all these great things, there’s also been a few hard lessons that’ve been great catalysts for personal growth. In line with this, I’ve added a “lessons learned” section to the format I gave last year’s brief year in review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-highlights&quot;&gt;5 Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-experience&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foxguides.co.nz/&quot;&gt;Best experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were lots to choose from here, but snorkeling with green turtles in Hawaii clinched it. There was a whole group just swimming up by us for air, and it was surreal how close they were. GoPro footage on it’s way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-city&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vsco.co/dominicsebastian/media/5673ac94e3544744578bcdfe&quot;&gt;Best city&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a really close friend in London, we took a trip to go and see a mutually close friend In New York. It was sensational. Completely exhausting but invigorating at the same time. Compltely lived up to expectation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-exhibition&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acmi.net.au/events/screen-worlds/&quot;&gt;Best exhibition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By pure luck we stumbled across this, but the Cooper Hewitt in New York had an exhibition on how  Pixar break down a story. It was small, but had all these little gems from their process on previous films. So much fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-blog&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtraction.com/&quot;&gt;Best blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like Khoi’s writing style. It’s interesting, feels conversational and unpretentious. And although I reduced a lot of things coming into my inbox this year, Subtraction is one of the few to remain. Really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-book&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Architecture-Happiness-Alain-Botton/dp/0307277240&quot;&gt;Best book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alain de Botton has been in my peripheral for years, but never actually read his work. This year I read the Architecture of Happiness, and regret not having read his books sooner. Really interesting and thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-favourite-apps&quot;&gt;5 favourite apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pocket-casts&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.pocketcasts.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 5 years late, but I really got into podcasts this year. I’ve been working through This American Life, and they’re great to run to. Pocket Casts won for me on it’s simple design, and keeping old show’s backlogs searchable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;letterboxd&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letterboxd.com/domseb/&quot;&gt;Letterboxd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d always saved my watchlist of films in Wunderlist. But I couldn’t track films watched, or get recommendations from others. Khoi Vinh (avid film watcher) mentioned it on Subtraction, and I’ve been hooked since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;spark&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sparkmailapp.com/&quot;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having Mailbox, the ability to defer and snooze mail is something I couldn’t be without. Airmail and Polymail were close, but Spark has the perfect mix of simple design and powerful features to win me over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thunderspace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thunderspace.me/&quot;&gt;Thunderspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat from last year, but worth it. I’ve always thought I was more creative/productive listening to music, and was skeptical of listening to rain, but this app can’t be beaten for focus work or meditating. Just amazing,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bobby&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bobbyapp.co/&quot;&gt;Bobby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of those apps that should just be included in your bank app but isn’t. Let’s me keep track of when my payments for various services will be due, so it’s easy to manage. Simple, and now has all currencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned-in-2016&quot;&gt;Lessons learned in 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest lessons this year can be summed up in two words – managing ego. This applies to my own ego, and the people I work with and manage. It’s something that as my responsibilities have grown over this year, and I communicate with more people in other timezones only over Slack, that I need to make a conscious effort to be better at. Things that helped towards the end of this year were &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/managing-ego&quot;&gt;managing ego&lt;/a&gt; from A List Apart, and frequently remind myself of Jason Fried’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&quot;&gt;Give it 5 mintues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-im-excited-about-in-2017&quot;&gt;Things I’m excited about in 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I wanted to travel, make more time for reading, meditation and writing – all wrapped up into a nice morning routine. I read more than half my reading list I set last year, far more than I did the year before. And although I didn’t write or meditate as much, I did get to get into some semblance of a fitness routine, and ran a few decent length races. In 2017 I’m looking forward to doubling down on all these, and launching a side project I’ve had on the backburner for too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review-of-2016s-reading-list&quot;&gt;Review of 2016’s reading list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last year I set this as my reading list for the year. Managed to get through just over half of it, which I was happy with, but still not quite the book a month I wanted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Google-Works-Eric-Schmidt/dp/1455582344&quot;&gt;How google works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1580194.Introducing_Aesthetics&quot;&gt;Introducing aesthetics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Language-Things-Understanding-Desirable-Objects/dp/0393070816&quot;&gt;The language of things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/architecture/&quot;&gt;The architecture of happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4064936-books-v-cigarettes&quot;&gt;Books vs cigarettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/travel/&quot;&gt;The art of travel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;❌ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ways-Seeing-Based-BBC-Television/dp/0140135154&quot;&gt;Ways of seeing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅ &lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/philosophy/&quot;&gt;The consolations of philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;❌ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/B-Bauhaus-Z-Modern-World/dp/0718199510&quot;&gt;B is for Bauhaus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;✅  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Intelligence-Flesh-Your-Needs-Thinks/dp/0300208820&quot;&gt;Intelligence of the flesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;❌ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Music-Got-Free-Industry/dp/0525426612&quot;&gt;How music got free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;❌ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Road-Character-David-Brooks/dp/081299325X&quot;&gt;The road to character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading-list-for-2017&quot;&gt;Reading list for 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I did realise from last year’s reading list though, is there were a few books that I really really tried to get through, but just couldn’t. I always get this weird feeling of guilt when I quit on a book, but for a few, I could have read 3 books in the time it took me to wade through one. This year I’m focussing on a few authors I loved in 2015, rolling over a few I didn’t get to, and chucking in a few scripts to the mix:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Art-as-Therapy-Alain-Botton/dp/0714872784/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487157472&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=art+as+therapy&quot;&gt;Art as Therapy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pleasures-Sorrows-Work-Alain-Botton/dp/0241144434/ref=sr_1_3?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487157450&amp;amp;sr=1-3&amp;amp;keywords=the+pleasures+and+sorrows+of+work&quot;&gt;The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Consolations-Philosophy-Alain-Botton/dp/0679779175/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487157428&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=The+Consolations+of+Philosophy&quot;&gt;The Consolations of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/architecture/&quot;&gt;How Proust can Change your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Writing-Emotional-Impact-Techniques-Fascinate/dp/1595940286&quot;&gt;Writing for Emotional Impact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hitchcock-Revised-Francois-Truffaut/dp/0671604295/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487157489&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=hitchcock+truffaut&quot;&gt;Hitchcock Truffaut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/travel/&quot;&gt;The art of travel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ways-Seeing-Based-BBC-Television/dp/0140135154&quot;&gt;Ways of seeing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sonyclassics.com/awards-information/whiplash_screenplay.pdf&quot;&gt;Whiplash Script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indiegroundfilms.files.wordpress.com/2014/01/the-shining-post-production-script-july-1980.pdf&quot;&gt;The Shining Script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slguardian.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Ex-Machina.pdf&quot;&gt;Ex Machina Script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.screenplaydb.com/film/scripts/Zodiac.PDF&quot;&gt;Zodia Script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016-review/</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Purging my Pocket</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I signed up for Pocket late in 2012, soon after it changed from Read it Later. Long after I had iPad apps that delivered RSS feeds in quaint little faux newspapers, and Pulse was ruined for me by LinkedIn  – Pocket looked like it had &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; solved my reading list problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was simple to use, elegantly designed, and had feature parity with everything else. I think what swung it for me was the cleverness of the brand. “When you find something you want to view later, put it in Pocket.” I loved it. With my new iPad accompanying me on an hour commute each way to work, it was also the first app I installed that actually did anything useful. The promise of a simple way to manage my reading list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 4 years, and the problem is I still can’t manage my reading list. A problem that’s not with Pocket at all really. It’s with me, and my terrible link hoarding talents. It’s with my private delusion that just by saving something to read later, I am somehow closer to having read it. Closer to being well informed. Closer to knowing who the latest whoever is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; with Pocket though, is the same problem with every read it later service. Their primary focus is optimising the speed of adding links, so they can surface links similar to that one I’ve saved. None of them have ever focussed on the retrieval side, and obviously couldn’t care less I’m not making any progress on my reading list. Saved a link in Pocket? Here, have an email that contains similar articles. Saved 412 links in Pocket? Here, have an email that contains similar articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So inevitably, I’ve arrived at this point of defeat in my reading list. I have hours and hours of articles I’m never going to get to, and piling on more daily. I have this overwhelming amount of reading obligations nagging away at me, making me feel bad for ignoring them. So I’ve decided to close my account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fear that one of these is so valuable I might regret not reading it forever (a classic symptom of pathological hoarding), I decided to have one final glance through my list. Half of the articles were already dated, expired either in meaning or content. Half were just repetitions of the same article said a slightly different way, presumably because I never got round to reading the original. Clearly not loosing much in the purge, but I wish there had been a way to not have added so much crap in the first place. Then I could have spent more time reading things that mattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove “Save to Pocket”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero reading obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/purging-my-pocket/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/purging-my-pocket/</guid>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personalisation starts with empathy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my first year studying Industrial Design at University, we were given a cautionary tale about the cost of not understanding who we were designing for. Meet the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/news/9951876/Sinclair-C5-voted-biggest-innovation-disaster.html&quot;&gt;“biggest disaster in innovation”&lt;/a&gt;, the Sinclair C5:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/sinclair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1988, the Sinclair C5 went from drawing board to prototype without any market research. Driven only by the founder’s endless optimism rather than by what the public needed, it sold only 5,000 of the 17,000 manufactured. The company went into receivership just few months after the launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had there been any real thought given to who might have used it, any empathy at all for what they might actually need, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sinclair_C5#cite_note-Cross-4&quot;&gt;“notorious example of failure”&lt;/a&gt; could have been easily avoided. My lecturer’s final slide on User-Centered Design read “know thy user,” and this tenet has stayed with me ever since, through everything I’ve designed. When I design Learning Experiences, the first questions I ask are, “Who is the Student I am designing for?” and “How can I feel empathy for what they need?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-off-personas&quot;&gt;Building off Personas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first practical tool for building empathy in the design process was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2008/05/the_origin_of_personas&quot;&gt;introduced by Alan Cooper in 1998&lt;/a&gt;, in his bestseller The Inmates Are Running the Asylum. Personas, as he called them, became a staple in design deliverables, after their effectiveness was proven project after project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ve gone through various iterations since then, but their purpose has remained consistent. With details such as names, ages, competencies, and brief back stories, personas act as a constant reference of the different types of people you are designing for. As an example, a traditional approach to a persona for a student might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/persona.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this traditional type of persona is great for creating surface-level empathy for someone, a persona needs to feel realistic in order to serve as a useful reference to the designer. It’s easy to include too much information without giving thought to the overarching structure. Personas are a great start, but to make them a more effective tool for creating empathy, we need to include more about the Learner’s context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understand-the-learners-context&quot;&gt;Understand the Learner’s context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Kelley, founder of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dschool.stanford.edu/&quot;&gt;Stanford Design School&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com/people/david-kelley&quot;&gt;IDEO&lt;/a&gt; — both world leaders of human-centered design practices—offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://dschool-old.stanford.edu/groups/k12/wiki/3d994/Empathy_Map.html&quot;&gt;Empathy Maps&lt;/a&gt; as a way to help round out the picture of what our Learners might need. These questions help shift our mindset to who our Learners are, and they provide great insight into what you can create that will help inform the learning design process. The questions are broken down into four categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Says -&lt;/strong&gt; What are some quotes your Learner’s have said?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does -&lt;/strong&gt; What actions and behaviours have you noticed?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinks -&lt;/strong&gt; What might your Learners be thinking?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feels -&lt;/strong&gt; What emotions might your Learners be feeling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even just spending a few minutes answering these questions will give us a clearer, more realistic picture of our Learner than we had with traditional personas. Applying these questions to our previous example might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/map.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-for-the-extremes&quot;&gt;Design for the extremes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you can’t create personas and empathy maps for everyone in the class, and you also don’t need to. Generally speaking, 3-5 will capture the majority of Learners, but you should be conscious of what’s best for your Learning Design project. Too few and you’re probably generalizing the traits too much and losing out on valuable details. Too many and you’re casting too wide a net, and you will lose the ability to produce an effective learning experience. Generally speaking, all Learners will fall somewhere on the spectrum between struggling to understand and struggling to stay engaged:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/spectrum.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learner-spectrum&quot;&gt;Learner Spectrum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By designing your learning experience to address these extremes, you’re able to focus on your most at-risk Learners. Although there is no ‘average’ student, creating a few empathy maps for the Learners that fall within these extremes will result in a better Learning Experience for everyone in the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t personalize learning in any meaningful way without having empathy for our learners. Personas and Empathy Maps are simple, practical ways to build this understanding into our projects, and they greatly benefit our ability to design effective Learning Experiences. Reference throughout your Learning Design process to put yourself in the shoes of your Learners, and don’t let your project be the next Sinclair C5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post originally appeared on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartsparrow.com/2016/03/01/personlisation-starts-with-empathy/&quot;&gt;Smart Sparrow blog&lt;/a&gt; on March 6th, 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 16:34:51 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/start-with-empathy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/start-with-empathy/</guid>
        
        <category>process</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2015 – A brief year in review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sage advice. Looking back on 2015 I’ve definitely been guilty, skilled even, of starting plans and projects without finishing them. Whilst this falls firmly into the “do this better next year” bucket for 2016, I wanted to have a quick look back at what went well in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-highlights&quot;&gt;5 Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-experience&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foxguides.co.nz/&quot;&gt;Best experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice climbing Fox Glacier in New Zealand, which should be a post all in itself. Got some amazing pictures (coming soon) and shots on the GoPro, and the road trip down there was pretty stunning. New Zealand really is beautiful country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-city&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vsco.co/dominicsebastian/media/5673ac94e3544744578bcdfe&quot;&gt;Best city&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best new city I travelled to was Queenstown on the south island of New Zealand. It was my first time in NZ the year before, and I thought the north island was great, but the south really is in a whole other league of scenic. The view down onto the city from the top of the Luge was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-exhibition&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acmi.net.au/events/screen-worlds/&quot;&gt;Best exhibition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to Melbourne for a long weekend (close contender for best new city), and they had an exhibition on at the Australian Centre for the Moving Image called Screen worlds. An interactive history of film in relation to advances in technology. Basically everything I love in one exhibition - it was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-blog&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/&quot;&gt;Best blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve dipped in an out of Signal vs Noise, the blog from the always amazing Jason Fried, but I’ve found myself returning to it more than any other in my list. Best post I came across was called &lt;a href=&quot;https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&quot;&gt;Give it five minutes&lt;/a&gt;. It really resonated beacuse I find it so easy to be reactive to everything, so definitely something I want to be more conscious of myself. Coming from a industry vet like Jason felt reassuring as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-book&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Creativity-Inc-Overcoming-Unseen-Inspiration/dp/0812993012&quot;&gt;Best book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best book I read was Creativity Inc, from Ed Catmull on how they built and run Pixar. He seems so genuine, and getting a peek behind the curtain on the processes and creative management at Pixar was fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-favourite-apps&quot;&gt;5 favourite apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ia-writer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ia.net/writer/mac/&quot;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iA Writer has been pretty indispensable for notes and general writing, and after trying a bunch I love how distraction free it actually is. Might just be because it’s not in a browser, but I’ve really enjoyed using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basecamp&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp I used a few years back at Digicave, but came back to it again for managing side projects, and loved how non-nonsense it is in comparison to other apps on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mailbox&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailboxapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mailbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mailbox was best way to manage email, it was just &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; well designed. From the authentication tokens to the app, it was perfect. Pretty devastated this one shut down. &lt;em&gt;Shakes fist at Dropbox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thunderspace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thunderspace.me/&quot;&gt;Thunderspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always thought I was more creative/productive listening to music, and was skeptical of listening to rain, but this app can’t be beaten for focus work or meditating. Just amazing,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;onetime&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onetime.today/&quot;&gt;Onetime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re friends are across timezones, knowing when they are available to see a message or a call is important. Onetime does this in a nice and visual way, and also easy to forecast call times. Simple and fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-im-excited-about-in-2016&quot;&gt;Things I’m excited about in 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to make more time for reading, meditation and writing. Sounds trivial but I want to have a morning routine that has all three of these, and making my own good coffee in the mornings. I only meditated a handful of times this year, and just need to work on it being a discipline that I actually stick to this year. There’s also hopefully going to be a lot of travel next year, which is my favourite thing to do, so really looking forward to seeing some new places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading-list-for-2016&quot;&gt;Reading list for 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember where now, but I read a similar year in review on someone elses site, and they were trying to do a book a month. I’ve really slacked off with reading for years, and wanted to give it a go to see how many I could get through. Here’s my list for next year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Google-Works-Eric-Schmidt/dp/1455582344&quot;&gt;How google works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1580194.Introducing_Aesthetics&quot;&gt;Introducing aesthetics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Language-Things-Understanding-Desirable-Objects/dp/0393070816&quot;&gt;The language of things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/architecture/&quot;&gt;The architecture of happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4064936-books-v-cigarettes&quot;&gt;Books vs cigarettes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/travel/&quot;&gt;The art of travel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ways-Seeing-Based-BBC-Television/dp/0140135154&quot;&gt;Ways of seeing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alaindebotton.com/philosophy/&quot;&gt;The consolations of philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/B-Bauhaus-Z-Modern-World/dp/0718199510&quot;&gt;B is for Bauhaus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Intelligence-Flesh-Your-Needs-Thinks/dp/0300208820&quot;&gt;Intelligence of the flesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Music-Got-Free-Industry/dp/0525426612&quot;&gt;How music got free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Road-Character-David-Brooks/dp/081299325X&quot;&gt;The road to character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015-review/</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
