<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Considered Design</title>
    <description>I like solving interesting problems, for things that matter. Product designer. London, Rio, now Sydney.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 08:21:29 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 08:21:29 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The rhythm of our weeks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve found myself in a familiar place recently. Opening Slack at sunrise, responding to emails at dinner, doing busy work before bed. The bookends of the 9-5 have drifted, blurring the boundaries of life and work. Days slip by like this. My weeks are busy but unvaried, a wall of white noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of us work is always at hand, with always more to do. Ticking off a todo here and an email there helps us feel like we’re being useful, we have a purpose. Weeks like these are fine if they are rare. A big push to get a project over the line, starting something new on the side. It’s easy for this white noise work week to become the white noise work month, and before long you’re on a slow road to burn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overworking like this puts all my identity and self esteem into one vessel, and it becomes how I define myself. It has an outsized impact on my mood, which makes me feel too reactive, and to be frank, uninteresting. When this happens I need to look at my week with a different lens. To spot how I can make space for things I want to nurture, and amplify the things I enjoy in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-my-ratios&quot;&gt;Reflecting on my ratios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I could work less (which would have made for an even shorter post), but this is only part of the problem. Working is a default state when I’ve got nothing to displace it, but the white noise work weeks is also a reminder of all the things I’m not doing. I want my weeks to have rhythm and variety, that help create months with balance and fulfilment. Easy and enjoyable things to aim for, but to help be more specific I sketched out a goal of sorts. Things I want to be doing less of, things I want to do more of, and things I need to make space for. All to set a new, more fulfilling balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/ratio.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some need to happen in a particular location, some can happen anywhere. Some need a lot more energy and focus, others are a way to relax. The art of fulfilling weeks is finding the right balance between these things, and defending their time against the white noise work week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taking-stock-of-how-much-time-i-have&quot;&gt;Taking stock of how much time I have&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years I’ve been a little obsessive over how other people spend their days. Little tidbits of how they find balance and time for the things they are trying to maximise in their lives. I’ve tried Jessica Hische’s Ultra-Schedule, borrowed bits from My Morning Routine, and the simple wisdom of Mr Bingo. For a brief period whilst dating someone in a tax bracket I’ll never be in, even anecdotes from Lunch with the FT. Between artists and financiers, there is a common thread that connects them all. They are very intentional with what they spend their time on, and at which part of their day they do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/old-day.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at my days, after a good night’s sleep and other hard commitments, I have about 4 hours free a day. This all falls into one space after dinner, divvied up between work and Netflix. This isn’t my prime time brain time, but is a great home for “make space for” things like reading and creative practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/new-night.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, willing these to happen has not helped. For these to actually take root I’ve had to put them where the bad habits start. Leaving a book in progress on top of the TV remote, or making sure the iPad and Pencil charged and ready to use. The more intentional I can be with this, the harder it is for the white noise work week to creep in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-my-days-better&quot;&gt;Starting my days better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m most creative, productive and receptive first thing in the morning. The earlier the better. Knowing this, and testing it’s limits, I moved my day back to the unholy hour of 5am. My new “selfish space”. I can work on whatever I want, and not feel like I’m displacing family time or sacrificing other spaces to work on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/new-morning.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again this isn’t perfect. Am I thinking and writing with perfect clarity at 5:06? Deeeeeefinitely not. For writing and side projects, these two hours are more than the energy and focus I have in the four after dinner. Like the “hour of sleep before midnight is worth two after”, but in reverse. Selfishly, spending time on myself first makes it much easier to focus and be present in the other spaces in my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-how-the-week-feels&quot;&gt;Reflecting on how the week feels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important space in my week is time to reflect. A handful of simple prompts, it let’s me think about how the rhythm of the week has been. What went well, what didn’t, and what should I change. As with most things in life, it’s far more about the feeling of how things contribute than the exact amounts. This used to be on Sunday night, but I’ve found this more easier first thing Friday morning. That way my weekends are obligation free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
  &lt;img class=&quot;multiply&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/reflection.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fulfilling-years-start-with-fulfilling-days&quot;&gt;Fulfilling years start with fulfilling days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a CEO once who had a mantra for hitting goals that went “daily, makes weekly, makes monthly, makes yearly”. A former statistician, he thought of this as a numbers game, but the compounding nature of it stuck with me. The time we spend in our days is how we’ll spend our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/year-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve been trying to “maximise” in my life has changed a lot over the years, especially since becoming a parent. The joy is being comfortable with that change, and re-scaffolding my week to support it. For now though, my white noise work week has faded. My weeks have their rhythm back, and I have a process to keep that on course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rhythm-of-our-weeks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rhythm-of-our-weeks/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The necessary exercise in writing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was talking to a close friend recently, someone who I think is a very good writer, who helps edit my excessive use of commas in sentences (he didn’t have time for this post), when he said he’s started to think of writing like exercise. A process that feels arduous and unpleasant, but once it’s all done, you just feel better for having done it. Another run under your belt. Another post out in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was funny because to me his writing seems effortless. Clever and witty opinions on a wide range of interesting topics. He’s got a nice balance of long and short posts, and for him, doing this on an increasingly regularly cadence is what’s keeping his writing skills in shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own writing, personal or published, happens very rarely. My personal best is I think is maybe 5 posts in a single year. My signature style is to find a topic I initially find interesting, hash out a first draft, then let it wither and decay in my drafts over the course of several months. Like a neglectful plant owner, apologetically watering a dry twig in a pot once a month, at the same time wondering why it’s not in full bloom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully for my health, I do manage to do slightly more exercise in a year. Current habit is a few runs a week, but a habit I’m happy to break, because as you’ll know if you’ve ever tried it — running is awful. Aside from listening to Off Menu during it, to convince myself through association running is fun, the only thing that has helped it be slightly less awful is varying the types of runs I do in the week. A mix of short runs, long runs and intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mondays are my short run days. Running loops around the local oval, it’s a bumbling 5k to ease me into the week. Purely and horribly pragmatic, this morning run is really just for two things. To signal to my weekend brain that it’s time is up, and to condition myself for the longer, more challenging run on Friday. The small joy of this shorter Monday run is I don’t need to think about it. No excessive stretching, no prep, just put my gear on and head out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My writing never gets these short runs, and it shows. When I’m stumbling through a frustrated attempt at a longer post, it’s not reading about how to be a better writer that’ll help, or give me the stamina to finish it. It’s the habit of getting a few miles on the clock here and there. Small opportunities to get a post out, however long, to break the cycle and release the pressure of finishing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy writing, so much more than I’ll ever enjoy running, so I’m wary of putting too much structure around it as a habit. Thinking of it like exercise though is the perfect way to quiet the thinking that every post has to attempt to break some personal PB, or be the best exercise I can get. Sometimes a brisk morning 5k is just enough to feel content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/necessary-exercise-in-writing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/necessary-exercise-in-writing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shot on iPhone, forgotten forever</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To put it mildly, it’s been a weird time for everyone recently. I was due to fly home to London for a visit in April, but because my Mum is in a high risk category, I’d be in quarantine for as long as the trip was originally booked for, and we needed to cancel the trip. Even if we lived next door we wouldn’t be able to visit now, but not being allowed to see her in London, or my wife’s parents in New Zealand, it makes us all feel a little further than we are. Our saving grace in all this? Mia’s Moments, our family WhatsApp group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve taken more pictures in my daughter’s first year than I have in the 5 parent free years before that. Every first and every fall is faithfully captured, and sent with a caption to Mia’s Moments. Her first day. Her first bath. Her first giggle. A steadily growing timeline of her life, which during this time of isolation, has been our fallback for family connection. With this group no one is missing out, and no group is closer than the other. In the best possible way, we’re all just at an arm’s length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/born.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/mia-passport.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/ball.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the chat we’ve talked about how lucky we are to capture and share moments like this so easily, and how different it was when we were kids. With film cameras, each picture had a mix of uncertainty and anticipation waiting for it to be developed. They had to be more selective about what moments were worth capturing, and having to pay to get them developed also created a sense of occasion. We used burst mode to capture Mia eating her first birthday cake. A disposable Kodak only had 27 chances to capture the entire day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve always loved about film though; it has the useful physical prompt to make you more likely to do something with it. To frame it somewhere, stick it on the fridge, or slip into a laminated photo album with a shorthand for the memory — “Dom, 4 months old, with Uncle Joe. Marsh Green”. Displayed in the hallway of your home, put on the mantelpiece, or on the dresser by your bed — you’re able to bring a memory into a place you want it to be remembered and relived, so it’s not forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mia’s Moments is the closest ritual we have for flicking through a photo album, but it’s more to dip in and out of than a way to cement them as memories, or to externalise them from our phones and into the home. What we all love about it, though, is that we can just scroll through it to feel close to each other. A shared family highlight reel. I find myself going through these images of Mia regularly, exhausted on the couch in front of something shit on Netflix, and often think about how nice a private curated stream would be for other groups of people and moments in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My photos are not in a place to make this easy — I’ve got nearly 20 thousand images on my phone, which makes it impossible to seperate something that is genuinely nostalgic from the sea of noise. My iCloud Library, with all it’s metadata and history of my travel, has no easy way to quickly curate and share something with people I’m thinking of. Lockdown or not, the thought of retroactively organising something I’ve been so mindless about feels too big to be worthwhile. Thousands of images spread over years in different cities, different jobs, and different social circles. Not exactly a tupperware drawer I konmari my way out of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think part of why we take so many pictures is there’s a tiny comfort in capturing a moment, even if it is an illusion of preserving it in memory. Colourful manhole covers in Japan, taken on a walk with friends in Hakuba. An ornate ferry token in New Zealand, during a trip for someone’s 30th. A picture of a pint from a trip home with a close mate in London — these are all moments I’d love to remember and relive, but have quickly faded from memory as soon as I’ve taken them and locked my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/hakuba.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/coffee.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/ferry.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Faded memories from Japan, Sydney and New Zealand&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some I could print and frame somewhere, there is a finite amount of space in my home to put them. What I’d find more valuable is being able to surface pictures of certain people and moments in my photos when I want to, or when would be meaningful to be reminded of them. The problem with this is my iPhone is completely unaware of the emotional context of my pictures and the people in them. Is that an ex, or an old school friend? A reunion, or a Monday? My first picture with someone, or my last?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a small but meaningful change adding a “People” tab to the Photos app, and connecting it to other Apple services. My closest friends live in London and New York, and we’ve got an iMessage group that must be nearly 10 years old, and is still active almost daily. The People tab could easily group photos of us through that group (the same way it does on the newer share options). It could show me the photos and memories we have together, and be a way to surface those natively in iMessage, or a path to FaceTime them directly from a memory in Photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wide-image&quot;&gt;
  
  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/pixar.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;At an exhibition with close friends visiting a Cooper Hewitt exhibition in New York&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;At an exhibition with close friends visiting a Cooper Hewitt exhibition in New York&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this kind of memory assistant to keep me connected to people I care about would also help me with the emotional labour staying connected can sometimes feel like, especially in times like this. Whilst I wait for technology to magically solve this for me, there are some blunter ways I might be able to fold this into individual practice. I could set a weekly reminder to go through images I’ve taken each week, to tag people and the missing context just outside of the frame. Create a location based shortcut to intentionally select highlights on my commute (whenever that’s a thing again). Share more moments in posts like these. Maybe private blog posts just for closest friends. This all might prove to be more work than it’s worth. For now at least, I have Mia’s Moments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/shot-on-iphone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/shot-on-iphone/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shortcuts for automated bliss</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well everyone, I’ve finally done it. I’ve cemented Shortcuts in my life, and I’m happy to say I’m well on my way to automated bliss. I’ve attempted to find this bliss a few times — with IFTTT, with the previously named Workflow, with the rarely working smart bulbs — but after getting the Apple Watch last year, setting complex things like laundry timers was easier, and the need for Syndrome like power ebbed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As 2020 rolled in though, I saw someone using a Shortcut to revert one of the most annoying behaviours in iOS (low battery mode being turned off after it hits 85%), and I started playing around with it again. Maybe in part because I can’t really code, but it’s both empowering and exciting to create Shortcuts, and there is a tinkering aspect to it which is deeply enjoyable. A feeling mirrored by Khoi Vin in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.subtraction.com/2019/12/04/shortcuts-and-screenshots-on-ios/&quot;&gt;his recent post on Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; — it’s also easily possible to spend far more time on them that they could possibly ever save you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a handful I’m using daily now, and think they’re at a place that others might find them useful now too. The music one below was even enough to make me switch from Spotify to Apple Music (currently not possible to automate or shortcut anything with Spotify), and having artwork again to browse through without being pushed to their own discovery sections, I’ve really enjoyed. Once I figure how to host these I’ll include the iCloud links so others can use them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;focus-work--approachable-work&quot;&gt;Focus work &amp;amp; approachable work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the right conditions to do focus work is really important to me, and it’s always boiled down to two things; removing as many distractions as I can, and and giving others the signals that I’m doing focus work so I won’t be disturbed. The more clear and repeatable the prompts and routine are for me, the more pavlovian my response is, and the easier I find it to get into that focus state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds silly (maybe even sad knowing I come from London), but the best focus prompt I have is rain in noise cancelling headphones. Combining that with no notifications flying into my view, and I’m as distraction free as it’s possible to get (handled by 1-3 in this shortcut).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing big noise cancelling headphones is a good physical signal you’re doing focus work (although as we know, not aaaalways respected), but at Qwilr we also have distributed teams, so I wanted to be able to signal it clearly on Slack to everyone is most useful to me. I’ve tried this a few different ways before (using a combination of IFTTT &amp;amp; Glitch), but it was really unreliable, and after a few maiden voyages just stopped working altogether. This new setup works perfectly, but to do the Slack shortcuts it runs you’ll need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/custom-integrations/legacy-tokens&quot;&gt;create your personal Slack token&lt;/a&gt; to replace mine, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/methods/users.profile.set/test&quot;&gt;use their methods here&lt;/a&gt; to spit out the url with your token.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a playback device (useful if I’m wearing headphones or not)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plays my Focus playlist (rain track)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turns on do not disturb on all my devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates my Slack status, sets me away, and puts on DND&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s me select a timer for how long I want to do focus work for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-a.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-b.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-g.PNG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The steps to run the Focus work Shortcut, including the Slack api call for setting presence&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set my slack status was a little more complicated (for some reason I couldn’t get it to work through the same url schemes as above), but found &lt;a href=&quot;https://routinehub.co/shortcut/2443&quot;&gt;this Shortcut from Jake Bathman really useful&lt;/a&gt; (he also has an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jakebathman/setting-up-a-slack-app-for-use-with-ios-shortcuts-e8e16b15d0f3&quot;&gt;accompanying post here too&lt;/a&gt;). His Shortcut let’s you put in a custom text status each time, but as I just wanted to set a specific one each time, I cut a few of the steps out, and now mine looks like this, with a step above this which uses text to set my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SlackOAuthToken&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image-trio&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;items&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-d.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-e.PNG&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/focuswork-f.PNG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Using variables and dictionary to set a specific slack status&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-to-my-discovery-playlist&quot;&gt;Adding to my Discovery playlist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My memory iiiiiis not great, and to help with that I’ve always had a habit of writing down songs I like as I hear them. A personal torture for me is waking up after being somewhere, remembering very clearly I heard a new/great/nostalgic song I liked, but having only maybe a melody of it I will never, ever be able to google and find. The problem before is I’d have this huge list of songs in Things, which I then had to look up in Spotify to play them. With this Shortcut, I’m able to bypass that list and add songs I hear directly to a Discovery playlist. I then have another Shortcut to play this playlist, ordering songs by oldest to newest, so I’m not just replaying the same songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps-1&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s me enter a search query&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shows me a list of matching song results&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can select as many matches as I want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selected songs are added to my Discovery playlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/discovery.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;An example using an art marker (1) and the level of detail in the capture putting a head(2) and a statue (3) onto a desk&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;An example using an art marker (1) and the level of detail in the capture putting a head(2) and a statue (3) onto a desk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facetime-roulette&quot;&gt;Facetime Roulette&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important background context on this one — I find staying in touch with people I don’t see regularly really challenging. I’ve never been great at it, but living in a timezone 11 hours ahead has made it much harder. Part of it is I detest anything that makes something that’s not work feel like work. So the idea of putting a call with a close friend in the calendar so we don’t forget to do it I avoid like the plague. Facetime Roulette is actually an idea for an app I had ages ago, and although it doesn’t have everything (ideally I’d want to bias the roulette to people I hadn’t called in ages etc), this shortcut gets me most of the way there. I’m going to use this for a few months, and if it hold the magical appeal I think having a roulette layer to staying in touch with friends will have, I’ll develop the concept out more into an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;shortcut-steps-2&quot;&gt;Shortcut steps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grabs a specific contact group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orders it by random&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limits the selection to one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FaceTimes that lucky roulette winner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- Note to Future Dom — formatting on auto save will break this file, because it will add extra /figuress at the end... --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;

  
&lt;img class=&quot;border&quot; src=&quot;/assets/blog/facetime-roulette.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-play&quot;&gt;Further play&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few other Shortcuts I’m playing with at the moment, but haven’t got quite right yet. All solving the big problems in life — fade out the nursery light and fade in white noise, triggering the office logo to do a rainbow loop on a launch — but I’ll keep tinkering and share them when they’re done. If you’re interested in creating your own, the best places I found were the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/shortcuts/&quot;&gt;Shortcuts subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://shortcutsgallery.com&quot;&gt;Shortcuts Gallery&lt;/a&gt;. Both buzzing with hobbyist creators, and also very eager to answer questions — enjoy 🙂.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/shortcuts-for-automated-bliss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/shortcuts-for-automated-bliss/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Purging my Pocket</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I signed up for Pocket late in 2012, soon after it changed from Read it Later. Long after I had iPad apps that delivered RSS feeds in quaint little faux newspapers, and Pulse was ruined for me by LinkedIn  – Pocket looked like it had &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; solved my reading list problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was simple to use, elegantly designed, and had feature parity with everything else. I think what swung it for me was the cleverness of the brand. “When you find something you want to view later, put it in Pocket.” I loved it. With my new iPad accompanying me on an hour commute each way to work, it was also the first app I installed that actually did anything useful. The promise of a simple way to manage my reading list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 4 years, and the problem is I still can’t manage my reading list. A problem that’s not with Pocket at all really. It’s with me, and my terrible link hoarding talents. It’s with my private delusion that just by saving something to read later, I am somehow closer to having read it. Closer to being well informed. Closer to knowing who the latest whoever is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; with Pocket though, is the same problem with every read it later service. Their primary focus is optimising the speed of adding links, so they can surface links similar to that one I’ve saved. None of them have ever focussed on the retrieval side, and obviously couldn’t care less I’m not making any progress on my reading list. Saved a link in Pocket? Here, have an email that contains similar articles. Saved 412 links in Pocket? Here, have an email that contains similar articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So inevitably, I’ve arrived at this point of defeat in my reading list. I have hours and hours of articles I’m never going to get to, and piling on more daily. I have this overwhelming amount of reading obligations nagging away at me, making me feel bad for ignoring them. So I’ve decided to close my account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fear that one of these is so valuable I might regret not reading it forever (a classic symptom of pathological hoarding), I decided to have one final glance through my list. Half of the articles were already dated, expired either in meaning or content. Half were just repetitions of the same article said a slightly different way, presumably because I never got round to reading the original. Clearly not loosing much in the purge, but I wish there had been a way to not have added so much crap in the first place. Then I could have spent more time reading things that mattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove “Save to Pocket”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero reading obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/purging-my-pocket/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/purging-my-pocket/</guid>
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
